JOSÉ M CARDONA MORALES

IT Professional

Tigard, OR 97223

josemcardonam@gmail.com

(503) 348-3111

Technology Enthusiast, Autodidact, Team player, Self-motivated, and capable of grasping and use new software and hardware technologies. Possess strong leadership, organizational, and planning skills.

I have 12 years of experience, as a Computer Technician and IT Technical Support.

My skills and experiences include computer hardware, help desk support, technical support general, servers management, network switches. My first language is Spanish and basic English.

I hold an Associate Degree in Network Technology and Application Development from National University College, and My CompTIA A+ Certification, Self-taught Cybersecurity.

Knowledge in electricity, electronic, computers, and graphic art.

Experienced with Apple Mac & PC Windows Platforms, Servers Management, high-end wireless networking.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer



WORK EXPERIENCE -----

Shipping Associate

Independent Stave Company - Lebanon, KY August 2020 to November 2020

Loading and unloading trailers, Safely operate equipment used in barrel handling operations, Heading and Staves materials handling

Team Member

TG Kentucky, LLC, KY USA - Lebanon, KY December 2019 to August 2020

Bobbin Winding operator - Brake Hose

- Responsible for supplying the yarn in the process of winding
- Ensure the quality and correct type of material which will be delivered to braiding area.

IT Technical Support / Shift Supervisor

Imperial Pacific International Holdings Ltd - Saipan, MP May 2018 to November 2019

Responsible for onsite inspection, preparation, installation and commissioning of end user PC or other terminal/peripheral equipment for access to system applications and any repair and maintenance services of such equipment, and other tasks such as IGT and Gaming Servers Health Check, Workstation Inventory, Support on Casino floor.

Technician

Aeorotek - Añasco, PR March 2018 to May 2018

Task of Repairing, installing, or building fiber optic lines and Copper wiring. In the networking infrastructure, communications equipment. Operate test equipment in order to detect faulty and perform the necessary repairs. OTDR, VFL, FTTH Fiber Optic Fusion Splicer, among another's tool.

IT Support – Service Desk

Imperial Pacific International Holdings Limited - Saipan, MP

August 2017 to December 2017

Provided technical assistance and support related to computer systems, hardware, and software. Responsible for answering queries and addressing system and user issues in a timely and professional manner. Supported casino floor and office operation.

System Technician

Hospital San Carlos Borromeo - Moca, PR, US

August 2013 to July 2015

Help keep system healthy, integrate new technologies, Backup, Update and perform Maintenance on the system, Common Tasks, Server Roles and Features. Manage Active Directory, Group Policy, Help Desk Support, and Technical Support in general. Worked on Switch configuration on the Networking Infrastructure, Improvements, and Update.

Electronic Production & Information Technology Operator

Hewlett Packard Enterprise - Aguadilla, PR

January 2008 to April 2013

Work with UNIX test system and yield of the computer processor from High technology Enterprise servers HP Integrity Superdome and similar models, also with functional problem diagnostic.



EDUCATION

Certificate in Network Security Fundamentals (CompTIA Security+)

Inter American University of Puerto Rico-Aguadilla

June 2017 to July 2017

Associate in Network Technology and Application Development

National University College - San Juan, PR

May 2015 to July 2017

Technician Certificate's in Small Business Proposal and Development

Department of Labor and Human Resources of Puerto Rico

September 2015 to October 2015

Technician Certificate in Electronic and Computer Repair

Universal Technology College of Puerto Rico

2005 to 2006

Technician Certificate's in Computer Technology Specialist.

/	*)
(Α.	,
		/

SKILLS

- · A+ Certified (6 years)
- Graphic Design
- Servers
- Spanish
- Technical Support (2 years)
- · Network Infrastructure
- VMWare
- Information Security
- Network Security
- Computer Hardware (10+ years)
- Active Directory
- · Help Desk
- Network Support
- LAN
- · Microsoft Windows
- DHCP
- · Windows Server
- Operating Systems
- TCP/IP
- English
- Network Monitoring
- Disaster Recovery
- DNS
- WAN
- Equipment repair



LINKS

http://pcreparo.byethost6.com/gdp/

http://www.linkedin.com/in/jmcpr



CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES

CompTIA A+ Certification

August 2013 to Present

CompTIA A+ certification are proven problem solvers who are able to perform critical IT support tasks including device configuration, data backup and recovery, and operating system configuration. CompTIA A+ certified professionals have demonstrated baseline security skills for IT support roles and are able to detect and remove malware, address privacy concerns, and troubleshoot core service challenges.

Dell Compellent Storage Center SAN - Administration and Advanced Management - LA.

2015 to Present

Dell Enterprise storage for virtualized data centers and the cloud - Compellent Administration and Advanced Management - LA. Dell Compellent™ Storage Center SAN



ASSESSMENTS -----

Technical Support — Highly Proficient

August 2020

Performing software, hardware, and network operations.

Full results: <u>Highly Proficient</u>

Work Style: Reliability — Completed

November 2020

Tendency to be dependable and come to work.

Full results: Completed

Technical Support — Expert

November 2020

Performing software, hardware, and network operations.

Full results: Expert

Basic Computer Skills: PC — Familiar

August 2020

Performing basic computer operations, navigating a Windows OS, and troubleshooting common computer problems.

Full results: Familiar

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.